First-Year Ph.D. Student 🕟 National Taiwan Universit

Taipei. Taiwan

☑ dcml0714@gmail.com | 🄏 https://d223302.github.io/ | 💆 @dcml0714 | 🞓 Cheng-Han, Chiang

About me_

I am a first-year Ph.D. student at National Taiwan University in Taipei, Taiwan. I am a member of the Speech Processing and Machine Learning (SPML) Lab, and I am very lucky to be advised by Prof. Hung-yi Lee. My main research interests broadly cover different aspects of natural language processing (NLP), mainly involving self-supervised learning, interpretability and analysis of NLP Models, adversarial attacks, and human evaluation.

Education

National Taiwan University (NTU) PH.D. STUDENT IN COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

Taipei, Taiwan

Feb 2022 - Present

- · Advisor: Hung-yi Lee
- Direct pursuit of the Ph.D. degree
- M.S student in Graduate Institute of Communication Engineering (GICE) at National Taiwan University from Sep. 2020 to Jan. 2022

National Taiwan University (NTU)

Taipei, Taiwan

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Sept 2016 - June 2020

Publications

Conference Proceedings

[1] Can Large Language Models Be an Alternative to Human Evaluation?

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

(To Appear) Proceedings of the 61th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers), 2023, Toronto, Canada

[2] How Far Are We from Real Synonym Substitution Attacks?

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

(To Appear) Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: ACL 2023, 2023, Toronto, Canada

[3] Recent Advances in Pre-trained Language Models: Why Do They Work and How Do They Work

Cheng-Han Chiang, Yung-Sung Chuang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 2nd Conference of the Asia-Pacific Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 12th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing: Tutorial Abstracts, 2022, Taipei

[4] On the transferability of pre-trained language models: A study from artificial datasets

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2022

[5] Pretrained Language Model Embryology: The Birth of ALBERT

Cheng-Han Chiang, Sung-Feng Huang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 2020 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2020, Online

Workshop Paper

[6] Re-Examining Human Annotations for Interpretable NLP

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Explainable Agency in Artificial Intelligence Workshop of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2022

Preprints

[7] Understanding, Detecting, and Separating Out-of-Distribution Samples and Adversarial Samples in Text Classification **Cheng-Han Chiang**, Hung-yi Lee

arXiv preprint arXiv:2204.04458 (2022)2022

Professional Talks

CONFERENCE TUTORIALS

ICASSP 2023 Rhodes Island, Greece

PARAMETER-EFFICIENT LEARNING FOR SPEECH AND LANGUAGE PROCESSING: ADAPTERS, PROMPTS, AND REPROGRAMMING

Tutorial speaker for parameter-efficient learning in NLP

AACL-IJCNLP 2022 Virtual

RECENT ADVANCES IN PRE-TRAINED LANGUAGE MODELS: WHY DO THEY WORK AND HOW DO THEY WORK

2022

2023

- · Main organizer of the tutorial
- Tutorial website: https://d223302.github.io/AACL2022-Pretrain-Language-Model-Tutorial/
- Tutorial recordings: https://youtu.be/thr4-hgLhi8

Honors & Awards

2022 **Elite Doctoral Scholarship**, National Taiwan University

Taipei. Taiwan

2021 Advanced Speech Technologies Scholarship, National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

Teaching Assistants _____

Machine Learning 2023 Spring

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Feb. 2023 - Jun. 2023

• Gave a 2-hour lecture on diverse topics of large language models.

Machine Learning 2022 Spring

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

Teaching assistant Feb. 2022 - Jun. 2022

- Gave a 2-hour lecture on the recent advances in pre-trained language models. Video is available: https://youtu.be/NzElV8jTNmw
- Gave a 3-hour lecture on the adversarial attacks in NLP. Videos are available: https://youtu.be/68lwXWFzCmg and https://youtu.be/68lwXWFzCmg

Machine Learning 2021 Spring

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Feb. 2021 - Jun. 2021

• Bulit, designed, and maintained the course website: https://speech.ee.ntu.edu.tw/~hylee/ml/2021-spring.php

Machine Learning 2020 Spring

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Feb. 2020 - Jun. 2020

- Gave a 2-hour lecture on graph neural network. Video is available: https://youtu.be/M9ht8vsVEw8
- Designed a homework on meta-learning

Deep Learning for Human Language Processing 2020 Spring

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Feb. 2020 - Jun. 2020

· In charge of homework on voice conversion

Research Experience ____

Supervisor: Dr. Hung-yi Lee

Taipei, Taiwan

August. 2020 - Present

- Analysis of self-supervised learning models in NLP [5, 4, 3]
- Adversarial attacks in NLP [7, 2]
- Human evaluations in NLP [6, 1]

Work Experience

National Taiwan University Speech Lab.

NTU Speech Processing and Machine Learning Lab.

Taipei, Taiwan

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR AND NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR

Feb. 2021 - Jan. 2022

• Managed a Slurm-based system with 20 GPUs

Professional Activities

PROGRAM COMMITTEE 2021-Present

- International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2023
- Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL) 2023
- European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL) 2023
- AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2023
- Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2022, 2023
- International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2022, 2023
- Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) –2021, 2022

JOURNAL REVIEWER 2023-Present

• Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing: 2023